# Josue Rodriguez

## Data Scientist, Quantitative Researcher

I pride myself on using my background in research and statistics to tailor principled and creative data solutions to unique business problems. I excel in collaborating with stakeholders across different levels and functions of an organization to improve and better understand exciting and meaningful products. In my off time my hobbies include: exercising, cooking, playing chess, spending time with loved ones, and writing R packages.

| $\succ$              | josue.rodriguez594@gmail.com      |
|----------------------|-----------------------------------|
| •                    | (925) 658-2924                    |
| 9                    | Davis, United States              |
| ::<br> \$\frac{1}{2} | josue.rbind.io                    |
| in                   | linkedin.com/in/josue-e-rodriguez |

### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Quantitative Researcher** University of California, Davis

09/2019 - Present

### Responsibilities

- Led all aspects of 4+ large-scale projects focused on developing complex statistical models and Bayesian methods and developed the core analytics for 9+ projects
- Engaged in professional collaborations across the US and internationally, resulting in 5 academic publications
- Authored 6 R packages on CRAN
- Taught > 60 graduate students about statistics, machine learning, and data science programming
- Awarded Outstanding Graduate Student Teacher

# **Data Science Intern, Data and AI** IBM

06/2022 - 09/2022

San Francisco, CA

### Responsibilities

- Helped develop the AI Fairness 360 R package and created a vignette demonstrating its functionality
- Worked on a cross-functional team of product managers and strategy consultants where I developed an analytics pipeline for one of IBM's Data and AI products
- Contributed to product strategy by delivering actionable insights using Bayesian statistics and predictive models
- Developed a questionnaire and an unstructured interview format to obtain data regarding product experience

# Data Science Intern

Spacee, Inc.

09/2021 - 12/2021 Dallas

Spacee leverages computer vision to empower orgs with near-real-time actionable insights for managing inventory and interactive consumer behavior.

## Responsibilities

- Developed an unsupervised machine learning model to help bring functionality to a remote sensing application
- Conducted exploratory data analysis around key company products and metrics
- Conducted field research concerning the company's operational envelope
- Implemented Python code into a core Airflow pipeline that addressed a deficit in the ETL process

## **SKILLS**



## CERTIFICATES

Data Scientist with Python (05/2019)

DataCamp

Data Scientist with R (05/2018)

## **LANGUAGES**

English Spanish

Native or Bilingual Proficiency Full Professional Proficiency

French

Limited Working Proficiency

### **EDUCATION**

**Quantitative Psychology, PhD** University of California, Davis

09/2019 - Present Davis, CA

# **Experimental Psychology, MA**Cal Poly Humboldt

08/2017 - 05/2019

Courses

Minor in Statistics

,

Arcata, CA